BRIAN VOJTKO

570-690-7340 vojtko.brian@yahoo.com Topton, PA 19562

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a Technical Recruiter with a passion for coding, I am eager to transition into a Python-focused role where I can combine my technical recruiting expertise with my growing proficiency in Python programming. While I have little professional experience with Python, I have been coding on the side for the past two years.

Currently, I use Python extensively to automate day-to-day tasks and boost productivity. I also built a Chrome app with Python, Flask, and web development to match LinkedIn candidates to jobs, demonstrating my ability to apply Python in real-world scenarios.

I am excited to bring my unique combination of technical recruiting and Python skills to a Python role and contribute to innovative projects!

SKILLS

- Python
- Selenium
- SQL
- Agile Methodologies
- Teamwork

- Flask
- Web Development
- Git
- Communication

EXPERIENCE

Software Recruiter, Hatch IT, Jun 2022 - Current, McLean, VA

- Sourced potential candidates through various methods, including job boards, social media, and employee referrals
- \bullet Used Python to automate everyday tasks and improve productivity by 50%
- Collaborated with account managers to understand clients' technical requirements to identify top talent
- Provided regular updates and reports on recruiting activities, such as candidate pipelines, interview feedback, and other relevant metrics
- Maintained strong relationships with candidates and industry professionals to build a strong network for future recruiting efforts
- Researched market trends to identify potential candidates for future hiring needs and build a talent pipeline for key technical roles.

Software Developer, Freelance, Aug 2018 - Current

- Developed a user-friendly Chrome extension using Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that enables efficient and accurate candidate-job matching based on their specific tech stack and years of experience. Hosted on AWS EC2.
- Designed and built an automated messaging tool using Python and Selenium for a LinkedIn Recruiter account that streamlines candidate outreach by automatically sending personalized messages to targeted candidates in a project's 'uncontacted' section.
- Implemented an advanced X-ray search capability using Python and Selenium that utilizes Google search and web scraping techniques to extract key candidate information such as name, job title, current

company, and LinkedIn profile URL and efficiently export data to a local CSV file for easy import into an ATS.

Associate Software Recruiter, Hatch IT, Jun 2021 - Jun 2022, McLean, VA

- Highlighted current job openings by crafting personalized recruitment emails.
- Sourced potential candidates through LinkedIn Recruiter, GitHub, X-ray searches, StackOverflow, and social media
- Collaborated with account managers to understand clients' technical requirements to identify top talent.
- Utilized Python to streamline recruitment workflows and automate timeconsuming tasks.

Identity and Access Management Analyst II, Integrated Project Services, Dec 2020 - Jun 2021, Blue Bell, PA

- Automated everyday tasks using PowerShell, including user onboarding and offboarding setup and procedure
- Implemented new company security policies and standard operating procedures
- Oversaw all helpdesk tickets relating to user access requests and adjustments
- Managed user credentials, licenses, and groups inside Microsoft Azure

Identity and Access Management Analyst I, Integrated Project Services, Aug 2019 - Dec 2020, Blue Bell, PA

- Automated everyday tasks using PowerShell to ensure appropriate user identities and credentials and controlled access to various resources such as folders, shares, servers, and applications.
- Created and maintained security and distribution groups within Active Directory and provided user access upon approval.
- Updated and applied multiple security policies and standard operating procedures essential to proper workflow and guidelines.

IT Support Analyst I, Integrated Project Services, Apr 2019 - Aug 2019, Blue Bell, PA

- Provided first-line PC hardware and software support through ManageEngine ServiceDesk+ to in-office and remote employees
- Investigated and resolved software and hardware issues for all users in a fast-paced environment and ensured maximum uptime and productivity for the end user
- Applied company domain image to new computers and assigned and documented each to new employees

EDUCATION

Post Baccalaureate Certificate: Computer Science Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA, Apr 2019

Bachelor of Science - BS: Criminal Justice Penn State University, State College, PA, May 2018